Paul Smith

55 Central Avenue, Dogsthorpe, Peterborough, Cambridgeshire. PE1 4LW.

TEL.07523756851

explorationsofnature@gmail

OBJECTIVE

After over 3 decades of enjoying the skilled labour of landscape gardening my body is telling me it is time to slow down physically.

While obviously sad at loosing what I chose to identify myself, this gives me the opportunity to Explore a completely different work environment. I know people who have worked in the office environment and the social, customer led mission has recently drawn my interest.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

While I have thoroughly enjoyed the physical contact with the land my college training and supervisory positions has encouraged me to continue to exercise the administrative side of my industry.

Interpreting site drawings for:-

Tendering/quotations

Ordering materials, plant and manpower.

Planning works

Executing said plans

Using Exel, Word and Email for:-

All above plus

Creating risk assessments, Method Statements and safe systems of work.

To gather evidence of production for invoicing.

To resolve complaint issues to customer satisfaction

This was made infinitely easier a decade ago with the increase in availability of smart phones.

Experience

Landscape Team Leader, Warwick Taylor Landscapes 10/10/2016-19/09/2018

The key responsibility was to project manage the soft landscaping of multiple sites. As such I was site supervisor for my company on many sites including The Ely cinema complex and the Wicks retail park at Ipswich.

Landscape Team Leader, County Grounds Maintenance 16/03/2013-10/10/2016

The key responsibility was to project manage the soft landscaping of multiple sites. As such I was site supervisor for my company on many sites including The Kings Lynn Innovation Centre and many school refurbishments projects.

EDUCATION

National Certificate in Horticulture, Wisbech, Cambs. College of agriculture and horticulture. 1989-1990

NVQ level 2 in Groundsmanship and Sports Turf Management, Melton Mowbray, Brooksby 1992-1993

LEADERSHIP

Whilst my problem solving abilities probably led to my gravitating into supervision roles they were tested and pushed to the limits by the inclusion of needing to encourage the best out of others. For over 2 decades I have with varying success worked as team leader or supervisor. I am lucky to be able to remember multiple sites drawings at once and be able to guide teammates through problems over the phone.

COMMUNICATION

A nice Segway to communication skills I have developed as a result of by interactions with colleagues and customers. Which if there is still the question of describing a person's weakness in today's interview fashion, communication was one I could claim in my early career. I have learned how my words and stance can cause others to experience negative feelings, as a result of this I always try to be mindful of everyone's possible reaction to my words and stance. This led to my listening more and developing interest in people I was interacting with. I still believe that I have a lot to learn with my communication skills which is one of the reasons I feel office work would benefit my personal development.

As part of my personal development I have started a You Tube channel to practice my media arts skills like, Photography, editing, script writing and speaking.